93. Yoga. The word yoga has many meanings. It can mean balance, unity, or joining. Broadly
speaking, yoga is a combination of mental and physical practices. Doing yoga is supposed
to help people achieve true understanding. It is unclear when people first began to practice
yoga, but the concept of yoga comes from the area of India and Pakistan and may be over 5,000 years
old. There are many different branches of yoga. We'll focus here on some basic principles they
all share. The most important part of yoga is breathing. Yoga starts with the correct breath.
Breathing slowly and deeply through the nose is the beginning of yoga practice. Later, people
practicing yoga may learn more difficult breathing exercises. Once your breathing is correct, you can
move on to doing poses. The poses, or asanas, are designed to create strength and flexibility in the
body. This relates back to the idea of balance. As you become more used to yoga, you can do more
challenging poses. Many people do yoga simply for the exercise. Yoga does indeed help people
become fit and healthy. But the idea is never to compete, only to do your best and improve at your
own rate. The difficult poses also help people learn grace under pressure. This means that,
though the body is struggling, the mind is calm. During a yoga practice, your mind is supposed to
be clear and empty. You think about nothing but the pose. In this way, yoga helps relieve
mental stress. The ancient tradition of yoga has spread to every continent and has been adapted
to many different cultures. If you walk through your town, you'll probably be able to spot a yoga
studio. Care to try it?